hearingdirect.com 2019-03-17

# Cookies & Privacy Policy - HearingDirect.com ™

This privacy policy sets out how we use and protect any information that you give when you use this website. We are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. We may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes.

  * Information collected by our website
  * Website Security
  * An Introduction to cookies
  * Your consent for cookie deployment by our website.
  * Cookies used by our website
  * Actual cookies deployed
  * How to disable cookies

## Information collected by our website

    * ### What we collect

For the purpose of making an enquiry or placing an order, our website may collect the following information. Your name and appropriate contact information including email address, address, preferences and interests. Other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers may also be requested.

    * ### What we do with the information collected

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with more information for the product(s)/service(s) you have requested. Your information may also be stored in a CRM system for Internal record keeping. We may use the information to improve our products and services. We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided. From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail. We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests. If at any time you wish for us to cease contacting you with items that may be of interest, please call us on 0800 0321301 or email customerservices@hearingdirect.com.

When you request information on or place orders for our products or services that are shown on our site ("Information"), through our online forms or otherwise, we may:

      * contact you by telephone, SMS, email or post with the Information;
      * contact you by telephone, SMS, email or post to confirm or verify your contact details or the details of your request; and/or
      * pass on your personal information and the details of your request to selected suppliers of the products or services for which you have requested Information, who may contact you directly by telephone, SMS, email or post.

We may also use your personal and other information in the following ways:

      * To contact you by telephone, SMS, email or post to ask about your experiences with the selected suppliers and request feedback. This might be in the form of survey questions, for example.
      * To contact you by telephone, SMS, email or post with information about other products and services (ours and third parties') in which we think you may be interested.
      * To pass on your personal information to selected suppliers of other products or services in which we think you may be interested, who may contact you directly by telephone, SMS, email or post.
      * If you consent, to pass your contact details, including your email address, to organisations that have a relationship with you to enable such organisations to update their records.
      * To facilitate communication between you and our customers (i.e. suppliers of some of products and services that are shown on our site).
      * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.
      * To enable you to access and use our site and services.
      * To ensure that the content on our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer, and improve our site.
      * To notify you about changes to our site or services.
      * We may also use, and provide anonymised aggregated information about our site users.

## Security

    * ### Website Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

    * ### Payment Security

We will take reasonable technical and organisational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information. We will never store your credit/debit card information on our website. All electronic transactions you make to or receive from us will be encrypted using SSL technology via GEOTrust and will be transferred and processed by **Worldpay**. Of course, data transmission over the internet is inherently insecure, and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet. You are responsible for keeping your password and user details confidential. We will not ask you for your password.

    * ### External Links

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## An introduction to cookies

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of our website.

### Cookies deployed by our website:

  * ensure that functionality operates as intended
  * remember your choices and preferences during and between visits
  * allow you to share pages via social network widgets like Facebook, Twitter and AddThis
  * allow you to interact with our website by leaving comments or opinions
  * post enquiries via our Anti-Spam enquiry form
  * track your visit for statistical analysis, allowing us to improve the usability, speed and security of our website

### Cookies are not deployed to:

  * collect any personal identifiable information (without your express permission)
  * collect any sensitive information (without your express permission)
  * pass data to advertising networks
  * pass personally identifiable data to third parties
  * pay sales commissions

## Your consent for cookie deployment by our website.

Upon your first visit to our website, you may have noticed our banner alerting you to the use of cookies by our website. In compliance with the 2011 EU Cookie Law, our website operates on an 'Implied Consent' basis. This means that we will assume that you have opted-in for our website to deploy cookies until you choose to deactivate them within your browser settings or via the instructions below. By default, the majority of popular web browsers automatically permit websites to deploy cookies onto your device. Below you can learn more about the specific cookies deployed by our website, and how they can be disabled. For more information on the EU Cookie Law in the UK, we recommend visiting the [Information Commissioner's Office (ICO)](https://www.ico.gov.uk/) website where you can find the latest information, guidelines and advice on the EU Cookie Law.

## Cookies used by our website

  * ### Social Network Sharing

We encourage users to share our content and/or like our on profile on the popular Social Media websites Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Google+ and LinkedIn. In order to make 'Social Sharing' accessible, our website utilises widgets either provided directly from the Social Networks and/or via amalgamative widgets from third parties such as AddThis. Cookies and privacy implications from the social networks vary and will be dependent on your nominated privacy settings with each Social Network. Social Sharing buttons will only deploy cookies if you are signed to that respective Social Network at the time of being on our website.

  * ### Analytical Tracking

Our website has Google Analytics installed which allows us to track and compile anonymous visitor statistics. The information collected ranges from simple traffic volume to the type of browser you are viewing our website with. This information is valuable to us not just for marketing analysis and quantification, but to improve the usability, security and load speed of our website content. Google Analytics is a popular, secure, flagship webmaster product from Google. The privacy and security of Google Analytics data is a high priority at Google that you can read more about on [Google's Analytics Data Safeguarding page](https://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html). Google also offer a [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) that will allow you to automatically Opt-out of all websites that track your activity via Google Analytics. No personal information is collected by Google Analytics.

  * ### Cookie Consent Check

As mentioned above, upon your first visit our website displays a banner at the top of the page alerting you about cookies being deployed by our website. In order for our website to remember your choice of opting-in, we store an anonymous cookie to remove the alert banner for 28 days. To prevent this cookie being stored, simply do not accept and close the alert. If you have already accepted the alert and you wish to remove the cookie, please clear your cookies within your browser settings.

  * ### Wordpress

Our website, either in full or in part, is built on the popular open-source CMS framework - WordPress. WordPress utilises cookies to allow visitors to register, login and comment on our website's content. If you do not wish to participate in commenting on our website, Wordpress will not deploy any cookies onto your device. Cookies will only be created by Wordpress if you actively register or comment via the clear forms on our website.

  * ### Magento

Our eCommerce website is built on the popular open-source platform - Magento. Magento and eCommerce platforms in general require the use of several essential cookies for the website to function correctly. A comprehensive list of the 25 cookies Magento may use are detailed in the table below.

  * ### Enquiry Forms

Visitors can choose to contact us via enquiry form(s) on our website. In order to prevent spam enquiries, we protect our forms with a 'CAPTCHA' challenge to ensure the submission is from a living person, rather than a computer bot. This CAPTCHA challenge creates a cookie that is used only to check the input response from the user is correct. The CAPTCHA cookie does not store any other information from your enquiry.

  * ### Google Maps/Places

Our website may have our Google Maps/Places profile embedded within an iframe. Google Maps creates cookies that enable the functionality of their powerful mapping software. No personal information is stored or shared on the cookies deployed by Google Maps/Places

## Actual cookies deployed

Below is a table of information which lists all cookies deployed and used on our website.

Cookie Category| Cookie Name| Cookie Description  
---|---|---  
Google | _utma | A Google Analytics cookie, which keeps track of the number of times, a visitor has been to the site, when their first visit was, and when their last visit occurred.  
_utmb | A Google Analytics cookie, which creates a timestamp of the exact moment when a visitor enters a site.  
_utmc | A Google Analytics cookie, which creates a timestamp of the exact moment when a visitor leaves the site.  
_utmv | Used for reporting in Google Analytics classifying the visitor.  
_utmz | A Google Analytics cookie which tracks where the visitor came from, what search engine was used, what link was clicked on, what keywords used, and where in the world the site was accessed from.  
PREF, NID | This cookie is set by Google Maps when you load a map of our location  
AddThis | loc, uid/uit, psc, di/dt, atuvc/bt/ssc/ssh/sshs/xtc | Allows users to share content via Social Networking websites and email  
WordPress | wp-settings, wp-settings-time- | This cookie verifies if you are logged into the website or not.  
wordpress_, wordpress_logged_in | WordPress cookie for a logged in user.  
comment_author, comment_author_email, comment_author_url | When you enter a comment on this site you will be asked to provide certain information about yourself including your name, email and website address.  
Magento | CART | The association with your shopping cart.  
CATEGORY_INFO | Stores the category info on the page, that allows to display pages more quickly.  
COMPARE | The items that you have in the Compare Products list.  
CURRENCY | Your preferred currency  
CUSTOMER | An encrypted version of your customer id with the store.  
CUSTOMER_AUTH | An indicator if you are currently logged into the store.  
CUSTOMER_INFO | An encrypted version of the customer group you belong to.  
CUSTOMER_SEGMENT_IDS | Stores the Customer Segment ID  
EXTERNAL_NO_CACHE | A flag, which indicates whether caching is disabled or not.  
FRONTEND | You session ID on the server.  
GUEST-VIEW | Allows guests to edit their orders.  
LAST_CATEGORY | The last category you visited.  
LAST_PRODUCT | The most recent product you have viewed.  
NEWMESSAGE | Indicates whether a new message has been received.  
NO_CACHE | Indicates whether it is allowed to use cache.  
PERSISTENT_SHOPPING_CART | A link to information about your cart and viewing history if you have asked the site.  
POLL | The ID of any polls you have recently voted in.  
POLLN | Information on what polls you have voted on.  
RECENTLYCOMPARED | The items that you have recently compared.  
STF | Information on products you have emailed to friends.  
STORE | The store view or language you have selected.  
USER_ALLOWED_SAVE_COOKIE | Indicates whether a customer allowed to use cookies.  
VIEWED_PRODUCT_IDS | The products that you have recently viewed.  
WISHLIST | An encrypted list of products added to your Wishlist.  
WISHLIST_CNT | The number of items in your Wishlist.  
  
## How to disable cookies

Most modern browsers allow you to control your cookie settings for all websites that you browse. You can disable cookie deployment completely by editing your browser settings, however in doing this you may be limiting the functionality that is displayed on our website. To learn how to disable cookies on your preferred browser we recommend reading [this advice posted by Google](https://support.google.com/accounts/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=61416).

If you are concerned about cookies tracking your movements on the Internet then you may be concerned about spyware. Spyware is the name given to a particular band of cookies that track personal information about you. There are many antispyware programs that you can use to prevent this from happening. Learn more about antispyware software - [https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spyware. ](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spyware "Spyware")As mentioned earlier in this page you can also disable Google Analytics on all websites by downloading the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).
